Priyanka Saggu

Resourceful DevOps enthusiast, having experience working with highly distributed infrastructure on hybrid cloud platforms. Having a years long experience as a DevOps Engineer, I've been writing fully automated product releases, with minimal interference on the client enterprise end. As a contributor at Linux Users Group of Durgapur, I have set up and managed multiple Linux-based servers. Wrote Infrastructure as Code (IaC) to automate setting up of tightly-secured and SSH-hardened systems/servers using Ansible & Jinja templates. Also, carrying an experience with On-Prem deployment environments setup using Rancher. And I'm an Outreachy'19 alumna at GNOME Foundation too.

Email: priyankasaggu11929@gmail.com

Website: https://priyankasaggu11929.github.io/

Gitlab-gnome: https://gitlab.gnome.org/priyankasaggu119 **Gitlab-salsa:** https://gitlab.gnome.org/priyankasaggu119

Github: https://github.com/Priyankasaggu11929/

EXPERIENCE

AtlanHQ

— DevOps Engineer

(MAY 2020 - PRESENT)

— DevOps Engineer Intern

(FEB 2020 - MAY 2020)

Working at a DataOps organisation, has resulted in a high level of expertise in writing & maintaining infrastructure for industrial use. In one instance, I've worked on optimizing the cost of running an entire data cataloging & discovery stack by 40%, bringing in a lite version of the product.

GNOME Foundation

— Outreachy'19 Intern

(DEC 2019 - MAR 2020)

Enhanced <u>GNOME Translation Editor (gtranslator)</u> UI by revamping existing widgets in accordance with Gnome Human Interface Guidelines (HIG). Besides, entirely redesigning the old search and replace bar dialog to a new sliding overlay style custom widget, using libdazzle library.

Linux Users Group of Durgapur (DGPLUG)

(JUN 2018 - PRESENT)

- $\bullet \qquad \text{Set up and managed multiple Linux distribution servers.} \\$
- Wrote Ansible scripts to automatically update system components and setup production environments.
- Set up a WriteFreely multi-user instance behind reverse-proxy.
- Set up multiple Docker containers, orchestrated using Docker Swarm, for carrying out test deployments.
- Wrote Infrastructure as Code (IaC) to setup SSH-hardened servers.
- Contributed to lymworkbook a Vagrant lab environment in setting up a few basic level sys-admins problems.
- Setup OpenVPN service, creating both OpenVPN server and Certificate Authority (CA) server on different machines.

Debian Project

(AUG 2019 - DEC 2019)

- Packaged 4 django/flask dependency python modules under Debian-Python-Modules-Team (DPMT).
- Packaged and updated 5+ ruby-gems for Debian-Diaspora project under Debian-Ruby-Team (DRT).
- Contributed to the Debian-gitlab project under Debian-javascript-team (DJT). Improved old node modules, packaged new ones and was constantly involved in testing of Debian-gitlab for then-stable version release.

WRITINGS

- Automating private dataproc cluster deployment having Presto Installation (on GCP)!
- Custom GCP type provider for automating VPC Network Peering Creation!
- Parse Server On-Premise Deployment
- A guide to a "safer" SSH!
- Consul Key-Value Store!
- Let's get started with intables!
- Automating WordPress Installation through Ansible!
- Setting up WriteFreely multi-user instance in production

EDUCATION

Deenbandhu Chhotu Ram University of Science & Technology, Murthal (Sonipat), Haryana
— B.Tech in Computer Science & Engineering

AUGUST 2015 - MAY 2019

Government Model Senior Secondary School, Sector 35-D, Chandigarh (U.T.)

— AISSCE (12th - PCM)

APRIL 2015 - APRIL 2019

S.B.P. D.A.V Centenary Public School, Fatehabad, Haryana

— AISSE (10th)

APRIL 2012 - APRIL 2013

SKILLS/ KEYWORDS

Linux: Debian family (Ubuntu, Debian Buster), Red Hat family (CentOS)

Scripting: Bash and utils, Python

Backend: Python (Django)

Frontend: HTML, CSS, Javascript (JQuery, PhaserJS)

GUI Toolkit: GTK+ 3 in pure C **Databases:** MySQL, SQLite

Web Application servers/proxies: Nginx, Apache2

Version control systems: Git

Markup & Documentation: LaTeX, Pandoc, Markdown

DevOps: Kubernetes, Rancher, Ansible, Docker, Docker Swarm, Helm/Helm Charts, Prometheus & Grafana, Loki, Velero, Weave Cloud, Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE), RabbitMQ, Replicated/KOTS, CircleCI, Github Actions

Misc: Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Amazon Web Services (AWS), OpenCV, Java-J2SE

CONFERENCES/ EVENTS

- 2019 PyCon, India
- **2019** <u>DebUtsav, Delhi</u>
- 2017 International Conference on Textile Advances-TAI India

REFERENCES

• Chandan Kumar, OpenStack/RDO developer, Red Hat, <u>chkumar AT redhat DOT com</u>